## Miguel Velez

Ph.D. Student in Software Engineering

2010 - 2015 UST Globally Minded Student Association

Carnegie Mellon University School of Computer Science Institute for Software Research ⊠ mvelezce [at] cs.cmu.edu '≜ http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~mvelezce/ in miguelvelezmj25

## "Premature optimization is the root of all evil" -Donald Knuth

	Education
2016 - Present	<b>Ph.D. Software Engineering</b> , <i>Carnegie Mellon University</i> , Pittsburgh, PA, USA. Advisor: Christian Kästner.
2010 - 2015	<b>B.A. Computer Science (Physics minor)</b> , <i>University of St Thomas</i> , St. Paul, MN, USA. Advisor: Patrick Jarvis. Summa Cum Laude. Cumulative GPA: 3.99/4.00.
	Research Experience
2016 - Present	Graduate Research Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.
	Research Intern, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, USA.
2014 - 2015	Undergraduate Student Researcher, University of St. Thomas, St. Paul, MN, USA.
	Industry Experience
2015 2016	•
	<b>Application Developer/Software Engineer</b> , Sportradar US, Minneapolis, MN, USA. <b>Jr. Application Developer</b> , SportsData/Sportradar US, Minneapolis, MN, USA.
	Cloud Developer Intern, Valtira, Minneapolis, MN, USA.
2013 - 2013	Cloud Developer Intern, Valura, Minineapons, Min, OSA.
	Awards and Honors
2015	MSRP Research Internship at MIT. Acceptance rate: 10.5%
2015	CCSC:MW 1st place Student Posters & Showcase Discovery Track. \$100
2015	UST Student Travel Grant. \$750
2014, 2015	UST Collaborative Inquiry Grant. \$2,000
2012	UST International Student Leadership Scholarship. \$500
2011 - 2015	Bev and Pat Flaherty Scholarship. \$14,000
2010 - 2015	University of St. Thomas International Scholarship. \$80,000
2010 - 2015	University of St. Thomas Tuition Scholarship. 40% discount
2008 - 2009	American Field Service International Scholarship.
	Other Interests and Activities
2014 - 2015	UST Game Design Club
	UST Computer Science Consultant
	UST Computer Science Club